

#### CONTACT

- [] (+91) 8285828880
- New Delhi, INDIA
- amiteascsm03@alumni.iimk.ac.in
- □ 11 Years O Month of experience

#### **EDUCATION**

2021

**MBA/PGDM - Operations** Swami Vivekanand Subharti University, Meerut

2018

**B.B.A/B.M.S - Management IEC** university

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- IIMK -Professional Certificate Programme In Supply Chain: Supply Chain Strategy & Management
- Advance diploma in computer application from **VJSS**
- Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

## **LANGUAGE**

# **AMIT KUMAR** RANA

LEAD - SHIFT INCHARGE

## **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Operational leader with 11+ years in e-commerce and retail, specializing in Supply Chain Management, Warehouse Operations, and Logistics. Skilled in optimizing efficiency, implementing Lean Six Sigma, and managing both international and domestic logistics to achieve financial goals and drive results.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 2024 -**Present**

## Lead - Shift Incharge **Flipkart**

- Managed the 400,000 sq ft warehouse for large segment operations, achieving a maximum dispatch capacity of 26k and maximum inward capacity of 15k in BBD.





- Oversaw a maximum built-up inventory of 500,000 shipments, with a pallet position of 22k.
- Supervised the inward capacity in the Return center of 3k and dispatch capacity of 1.5k

## 2022 - 2023

## Manager **TATA** croma



- Managed retail and e-commerce operations for optimal customer experience.
- Oversaw a 300,000 sq ft warehouse serving 166 stores in Delhi NCR, enhancing logistics and inventory management.

2018 - 2022





http://linkedin.com/in/amit-rana-19257354



## **Flipkart**

- Managed end-to-end NL-FC operations, including inbound, outbound, and returns.
- Optimized inventory management to reduce stockouts and overstock.
- Streamlined processes for improved returns center efficiency.

2014 - 2018





- -Managed primary and secondary logistics operations
- Oversaw inventory management activities
- Directed transportation management processes